Two men, one face.
The Scapegoat is a mystery, drama, adventure film directed by Charles Sturridge.
In 1952, as England prepares for the coronation, two very
different men have one thing in common—a face.
John / Johnny, played by Matthew Rhys.
Blanche, played by Jodhi May.
Lady Spence, played by Eileen Atkins.
Nina, played by Sheridan Smith.
Paul, played by Andrew Scott.
Charlotte, played by Phoebe Nicholls.
The Scapegoat is a British film adaptation of Daphne du
Maurier's 1957 novel of the same name.
The drama is written and directed by Charles Sturridge and stars Matthew
Rhys as lookalike characters John Standing and Johnny Spence.
It was broadcast on ITV on 9 September 2012.
The novel was first adapted into film in 1959 by director Robert Hamer, with Alec
Guinness playing the parts of John Barratt and Jacques de Gué.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.